

### **CONTACT**

™ m.sridhar2002@gmailcom

9840705555

• Chennai

in SRIDHAR M

### **SKILLS**

ADMINISTRATIVE SKILLS

**ADAPTABILITY** 

**COMMUNICATION** 

PROCUREMENT SKILLS

**COMPUTER** 

### **LANGUAGES**

ENGLISH

TAMIL

HINDI

FRENCH

### **M SRIDHAR**

#### **EXECUTIVE CHEF**

### **SUMMARY**

I have been working as Executive Chef for most of the popular hotels in the city.

I hold an experience of 20+ years effectively managing all tasks and leading the food department to the best of my abilities.

To lead the food production department for a challenging assignment being result oriented and enterprising.

### **EXPERIENCE**

## **Executive Chef JP HOTEL**

Dec 2013 - Aug 2021

With an overall experience of 7 years at JP hotel, I have successfully carried out the below projects.

ISO 9001:2015 for JP hotel kitchen, Chennai

ISO 22000 for JP hotel kitchen, Chennai

Food festivals

Major banqueting in JP hotels Chennai with turnover of food sales upto 11-12 cr per year

Operations of the Kitchens

Assisted in the opening of the Roof Top restaurant "Rajputana"

Solely responsible for the recruitment of Kitchen staff.

Procurement of consistent quality of materials required for he Purchase department.

Provided innovative and artistically superior and cost efficient food and beverage products that enhance the reputation of all the food outlets at the same time meeting the established quality and presentation standard

Developed system and procedures that achieve higher cost efficiency and guest satisfaction.

Devised methods for optimal use of raw material and fuel and maintain the budgeted food cost.

Worked in association with the F&B Manager in the area of promotion of food festivals menu planning, pricing.

Thorough knowledge of different cuisines their cooking styles, hygiene and safety standards.

Techniques in quality food production and dispensing.

Reviewed the monthly reports and developed work plan.

Coordinated with Chief Engineer for preventive maintainance ,procurement of new equipment, energy consumption etc.

Ensured through regular monitoring of guest feedback prompt efficient and accurate service to all guests along with best of quality products.

Staffing and schedule staff in order to optimize manpower done.

Established quality and quantity standards of food preparations and presentations.

Developed and standardized new recipes in order to add variety to the F&B outlets.

# **Executive Chef E Hotel [Express Avenue]**

2013 - 2014

Involved in setup /preopening of Banquet kitchen at E Hotel Chennai.

Conducted food festivals at Entrée restaurant, E Hotel Chennai

# **Executive Chef Raj Park Hotels**

2011 - 2012

Actively involved in the reclassification to four star of RajPark Hotel, Chennai

Conducted weekend food festivals

#### Corporate Executive Chef Poppys Hotels, Thiruppur

2007 - Mar 2011

Overall Work Experience at Poppy Hotel, Thiuppur

2007 - 2011 / 1996 - 2000

Multi Cuisine Menu Engineering done twice @ Poppys Hotel, Tirupur.

Conduted vaious food fesivals.

Conducted cookery demonstration in batch for two days

Designed, organized and executed Christmas and New year menus/buffet spreads.

Catered to India Knit Fair, Tirupur from 1997 to 1999 - winter and summer fair. 2007-2011

# **Executive Chef Best Western Pleasant Days Hotel ,Chennai**

2001 - 2005

Inaugurated Kitchen operations at Best Western Pleasant Days Hotel.

Main functions include indenting, menu planning, Staffing, maintaining the quality and consistency of food and Day to day operations of the kitchen.

Inaugurated and operated 3 fast food restaurants at Queensland amusement park Chennai-Affiliated to Pleasant Days Hotel. Caters to a crowd of 750 -1000 pax daily.

Sous Chef Savera Hotels

1995 - 1996

Chef De Partie
Gulf Hotels[Gulf Air]

1992 - 1993

### **EDUCATION**

IHMCTAN 1988

Institute of Hotel Management, Catering Technology and Applied Nutrition. Taramani

Diploma in Hotel Management and Catering technology

**Bachelor of Arts [B.A] - Economics** University of Madras 1988

### **PROJECTS**

## FOOD DEPARTMENT - PROJECTS Executive Chef

ISO 9001:2015 & ISO 22000 for JP hotel kitchen, Chennai.

Assisted in the opening of the Roof Top restaurant "Rajputana" - JP Hotel

Involved in setup /preopening of Banquet kitchen at E Hotel Chennai.

Multi Cuisine Menu Engineering done twice @ Poppys Hotel, Tirupur.

Actively involved in the reclassification to four star of RajPark Hotel.

Inaugurated and operated 3 fast food restaurants at Queensland amusement parkChennai-Affiliated to Pleasant Days Hotel.